Product Designer

Oluwatimilehin Akapo

PROFILE SUMMARY —

I am Oluwatimilehin! An empathetic, pragmatic, and versatile product designer with over 5+ years of experience in understanding user needs and wants and being able to translate these insights into conceptual and visual design while aligning with the business goals. I have experience working across E-commerce, Edtech, and Healthtech. I am Interested in putting my knowledge of product design to use by providing high-caliber work that will benefit any organisation.

WORK EXPERIENCES -

Product Designer (EdenLife) Full-time

October 2021 - Present

- Translated business goals and ideas in PRD to fully functional and usable prototypes.
- Illustrated design ideas using sketches, wireframes, storyboards, mockups and flows.
- · Worked closely with Product Managers, Frontend and backend developers to create scalable solutions.
- Designed a business dashboard using a combination of quantitative and qualitative insights to help inform design choices.
- Examined existing solutions to identify and solve user experience problems
- Effectively convey conceptual ideas, detailed designs, and design decisions using both verbal and visual methods.

Product Designer (Jeetar Technologies) Full-time

August 2021 - October 2022

- Created scenarios, use cases, and high-level user requirements based on business requirements, usability findings, and market research data for three entirely different products.
- Defined user personas and archetypes to represent two of our target audiences, information architecture, user flows, sketches, conceptual wireframes, mock-ups, and functional prototypes.
- Designed a concise sign-up process by combining quantitative and qualitative insights that led to a 96% in Customer Effort Score (CES).
- Conducted surveys and usability testing to gather users' feedback, these feedbacks were implemented and led to increased customer retention and satisfaction by 95%.
- Designed high-fidelity prototypes of over 200+ screens using Design Systems to maintain a high degree of quality and consistency across existing products design.
- · Collaborated directly with the product engineering department's developers to bring ideas to life: this generated about 4K+ users meeting 85% of the projected metrics for the beta phase.

CONTACT -

akapooluwatimilehin@gmail.com

(234) 81 6919 3439

Lagos, Nigeria

Linkedin

PORTFOLIO -

Behance

TECHNICAL SKILLS -

Design Thinking Ux Research

Sketching

Wireframing

Rapid Prototyping

User-Centred Designs,

Heuristic Evaluation

Usability Testing

Micro-Interactions

User Experience Audits Design System

User Interface Design

Responsive Design

Qualitative and quantitative data

SOFT SKILLS —

Collaboration

Growth Mindset

Versatility

Clerical

Creative Thinking

Team Work

Communication

Emotional Intelligence

Logical

TOOLS -

Fig jam Notion Adobe Xd

- Onboarded about 4k+ users in the first six months during beta testing: generating about
- Three launched products on Appstore/Playstore: Mobile App, Rider App, Merchant App.

UI/UX Designer (ZSoftware) Full-time

April 2021 - August 2021

- Implemented the Human-Centred Design, Design Strategy, and Design Thinking on three different products.
- Introduced data-driven design decision-making on the products, making it accessible to • Analysed to product owners/stakeholders how understanding users resulted in a spike
- in customers retention by 10%. • Redesigned website based on users' feedback that led to an improved Customers' Error
- Scores by 10%, updated the design documentation and proposed improvements to existing applications.
- Identified and troubleshot four edge cases to create the best possible solution.
- · Revised existing product roadmaps, feature prioritizations, and product backlogs for three different brands alongside Product Managers.

UI/UX Designer (Dira Labs) Full-time

November 2020 - May 2021

- Analysed quantitative data and qualitative data to help drive product and design. decisions to increase customer retention rate by 15%.
- Performed competitive and heuristic analysis on over six websites.
- Conceptualised and proposed ideas on ways to improve products accessibility by 60%. • Contributed to the development, maintenance, and continuous improvement of
- usability, ROI, and design standards of over three products.

User Researcher (NURHI) Contract April 2017 - August 2020

• Worked closely with the team to identify research objectives.

- Developed a well-crafted research plan with clear research objectives.
- Recruited targeted end-users for specific research studies.
- Crafted personas and other "information radiators" (e.g. journey maps) to communicate
- insights across the design and development teams. • Translated user insights into actionable recommendations for the team.

VOLUTEER -

with technical issues.

Design Mentor at SheCodeAfrica (SCA) • I actively mentor new product designers: I have helped a number of them successfully

launch their careers; this included but wasn't limited to giving advice and helping them

Framer Sketch Adobe Illustrator Adobe After Effects Adobe Photoshop Whimsical Wordpress HTML **CSS** Javascript

EDUCATION -

Animal Breeding and genetics: Federal University of Agriculture, Abeokuta

January 2016 - January 2021

CERTIFICATIONS -

Data-Driven Designs: Quantitative Research for UX

Interaction Design Foundation

Visual Design: The Ultimate <u>Guide</u>

Interaction Design Foundation

Agile Methods for UX Design Interaction Design Foundation

Fundamental Training in

Product Design Treford

User Interface/User

Experience Design

SheCodeAfrica

User Interface Design Essentials (UI/UX Design)

Udemy **User Experience: The**

Beginner's Guide Interaction Design Foundation

LIVE PROJECTS — Jeetar: (<u>Website</u>), (<u>los</u>) & (<u>Android</u>)

Jeetar Riders: (<u>Android</u>)

Faramove: (Website), (los) & (Android)